A Guide to the Robert P. Buford Papers 1966-1988
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Buford, Robert P. Papers 1966-1988
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 289
1 linear feet
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use wihtout restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated to the Special Collections and Archives Department by Robert P. Buford in December 1990.
Biographical Information
Mr. Buford was the negotiator between the City of Richmond and the County of Henrico who was responsible for a twenty year utilities contract. He was also the chairman of the Task Force that evaluated the need and potential for expanded port facilities in the central Virginia area.
Scope and Content Information
The collection consists of correspondence, reports, memoranda, minutes and plans concerning the negotiation of a water-sewer agreement between the City of Richmond and the County of Henrico and the working papers of the James River Port Study Task Force.
Arrangement
Arrangement
The correspondence is filed in reverse chronological order.
Organization
All other materials are in original order and labelled by Mr. Buford.
Series I--Richmond-Henrico Water Contract (n.d., 1966-1968)
Series II--James River Port Study Task Force (n.d., 1983-1988).
Contents List
- Series I--Richmond-Henrico Water Contract
  - Acts of Assembly n.d. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Analysis of the Cost of Water Service 1967 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - City-County Water Contract 1968, n.d. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Clippings n.d. (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Correspondence 1967-1968 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Henrico County Annual Report 1966 (Box-folder 1:6)
- Series II--James River Port Study Task Force
  - Consultants Agreement 1987 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Correspondence 1987 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Correspondence 1988 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Martin O'Connell Associates Proposal 1987 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Miscellenous 1987, n.d. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Phase I--Final Report 1987 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Phase II--Draft Final Report (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Phase II--Final Report (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Phase III--Draft Report 1988 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Phase III--Final Report 1988 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Port of Richmond Commission Annual Reports 1983-1986 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Technical Memorandum (Box-folder 2:10)